# Syed Subhan Uddin Hyder

Role: Senior Web Application Developer Skills: Frontend Developer Email: <u>subhanshah.22@gmail.Com</u> Mobile: +971 52 409 7627

Location: Al Qusais - Dubai - United Arab Emirates.

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/syed-subhan-uddin-hyder-a69993b9/



# **Profile Summary**

Professional Software Engineer with **7+ Years of Software Development Experience** Building, Integrating, Testing, Design and Development of large-scale cloud-based enterprise applications. Hands on experience with **MVC design patterns**.

Provide Quality Code with Maximum Performance Optimization and Responsive multiple screen Layout. Always Tends to Apply new Tools and Technologies.

# Technical skills:

#### Languages

- Html 5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, WordPress, Reacts Js, Tailwind CSS, Material UI.

#### **Software & Technologies**

- React JS: Advance Professional Experience
- MySQL: Advance Professional Experience
- JavaScript, jQuery & AJAX: Advance Professional Experience
- Bootstrap, CSS, HTML5: Advance Professional Experience

## IDE

Visual Code, PhpStorm, Sublime, Dart Pad, Notepad++, Visual studio, Dreamweaver

#### Servers

**XAMPP** 

#### **Databases**

My SQL

#### **Version Control**

Git, Jira

# **Design Pattern / Technologies**

MVC, Laravel Repository Pattern

# **Payment Gateways**

PayPal, Stripe

#### **Experience**

#### **Univations Design - Dubai**

(Jan 2023 – Present) Web Developer

- Designing Website in WordPress Framework
- Maintenance of WordPress websites
- Theme Integration
- Plugin Integration
- Payment Method Integration
- E-Commerce / Woo commerce Website on WordPress Framework
- Creating Social Media Post
- Managing Social Media Accounts
- Support in web service

#### H n H Tech Solutions - Karachi

(April 2018 – November 2022) Senior Web Developer (Core/ UI/ UX/ReactJS)

- Interpret application designs and systems requirements according to client requirements.
- Observe strict Constraints & Policies related to application Methods and Quality Standards.
- Adapted Agile Process in projects for rapid feature development and overcome market competitions.
- Responsible to Manage, Collaborate, Analyze, Plan Project Strategy, Design, Develop Web Applications,
   Debug, Maintain Code Quality, Integrate Databases Systems.
- Responsible for Front-end and Back-end designing and coding parallelly in multiple dynamic projects.
- Performed Application Analysis to enhance performance and Code Quality.
- Provided Task Management, every Sprint Distributed Tasks accordingly.
- Managed server-side configurations for domain, hosting and installation.
- Performed client meetings for technical discussions and project understandings.
- Technologies integrated Php Laravel, MySQL, Bootstrap, JavaScript, ReactJS

#### Intranet Solutions - Karachi

(July 2016 – March 2018) Senior Web Developer

- Interpret application designs and systems requirements according to client requirements.
- Observe strict Constraints & Policies related to application Methods and Quality Standards.
- Responsible to Collaborate, Design, Develop Web Applications, Debug, Maintain Code Quality, Integrate Databases Systems.
- Responsible for Front-end and Back-end designing and coding parallelly in multiple dynamic projects.
- Technologies integrated Php Codelgniter, MySQL, WordPress, HTML5, JavaScript

#### Buffalo Web Work - Karachi

(Aug 2015 to June 2016) Web Developer

- Provide time estimates of product based on finalized requirements and architecture.
- Create architectural design patterns using MVC, local MYSQL database and communication between server side and client side.
- System analysis and designing.
- Conduct Tech-session to promote a learning environment in the organization.

- Always takes responsibility for the project and completes it on the communicated date.
- Report directly to the Software Development Manager.
- Write, modify and test the high-quality codes for web application.
- Design website templates using HTML, CSS and develop websites using Php Codelgniter.
- Designed, customized and integrated Several WordPress themes and plugins.
- Write code for the new features as well as working on the existing features.
- Technologies integrated Php Codelgniter, MySQL, WordPress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

#### Bit Cloud Global - Karachi

(Jan 2015 to June 2015) Web Developer

- Developed Responsive Website and compatible for multiple devices
- System Analysis and Designing.
- Database Designing and Development.
- Write, Modify and Test the High-Quality Codes for Web Application.
- Design Website Templates using HTML, CSS and Develop Websites using Php Core
- Customization and development in WordPress.

#### Dev hunk Software Technologies - Karachi

(July 2014 –Dec 2014) Junior – Web Developer

- Designing Website in WordPress Framework
- Maintenance of WordPress websites
- Theme Integration
- Plugin Integration
- Payment Method Integration
- E-Commerce / Woo commerce Website on WordPress Framework
- PSD to HTML
- HTML to PDF

# **Major Projects:**

#### La Fresh

http://lafreshonline.com

- Developed a website for a Cosmetics selling company in UAE.
- Technologies Integrated WordPress, MySQL

# Independent Marble

https://www.independentmarble.com

- Developed a website for a Marble, Stone, etc selling company in UAE.
- Technologies Integrated WordPress, MySQL

## Dayalmc

https://dayalmc.com

- Developed a website for a container manufacturing is a company in the Arabian Gulf.
- Technologies Integrated WordPress, MySQL

#### Al Fatah

http://alfatah.org/

- Developed a website for multipurpose services including job portal, travel agencies, and consultancy.
- Technologies Integrated Laravel, MySQL, Ajax, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery

#### **House Runs For Me**

http://houserunsforme.com/

- Design and developed a Dynamic website for Maintenance Services provider company. We
  developed a platform where anyone can hire electrician, plumber, etc. to fix their
  problems.
- Technologies Integrated Laravel, MySQL, Ajax, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery

## **Family Handbook**

https://myfaminc.com/

- Developed a web application to Manage financial and insurance records for entire family.
- Technologies Integrated Laravel, MySQL, Ajax, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery

#### Sweat Furry

https://www.sweatfury.com/

- Developed a website for fitness company to Manage online subscriptions and provide online exercise trainings.
- Technologies Integrated Laravel, MySQL, Ajax, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery

#### Ghawali

https://ae.ghawali.com/

- Developed a website for a perfume selling company in UAE.
- Technologies Integrated Laravel, MySQL, Ajax, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery

# **Virtual Triage**

https://www.virtualtriage.ca/

- Virtual Triage is a Canadian based company.
- Developed a website for Online OPDs, Online checkups from registered clinics, doctors and hospitals.
- Technologies Integrated Laravel, MySQL, Ajax, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery

# **Legal Lands**

https://legallands.com/

- Legal Lands is an **Indian based company.**
- Developed a website for Legal Advisory.
- Technologies Integrated WordPress, and JavaScript

# **Education:**

# Institute of Business and Technology (IBT)

2012 - 2016

• B.S.C.S (Bachelor of Science in Computer Science)